Abraham: We have all seen and heard
references to the Dark Web on TV and in
the movies and have an idea of what it is.
This is where all those cyber
criminals hang out, sell their
tools and offer their services.
But this criminal underground
involves a lot more.
The Dark Web isn't indexed by search
engines but can be accessed by those
who wish to use a special browser and
almost anything that has a link to
criminal enterprise can be found there.
Navigating it isn't easy as it is
chaotic as everyone is anonymous
and scammers often move around
so as to avoid their victims.
The Dark Web has flourished
because of 'bitcoin' this crypto
currency enables parties to
conduct transactions anonymously.
Nearly all sites conduct transactions
using bitcoin, but the nature of the Dark
Web means that it's not always safe to
do business there, after all the place is
full of scammers and criminals and we all
know there is no honour amongst thieves.
But saying that the Dark Web is
not all about illegal activities
it offers opportunities for
journalists and whistle-blowers to
air their views and is monitored
by mainstream media organisations.
It also offers space for individuals
from less open societies to access and
have a voice in an anonymous environment.
Nicole: The opportunities for using cloud
services are there for everyone from large
companies and organisations to you and I.
Cloud services host software such as Adobe
Creative Cloud and offer subscriptions for
anyone who wishes to use their services.
No longer do individuals have to
buy expensive software that they may
not use very often, that has to be
updated or replaced when out of date.
Whilst they’re subscribed all software
is regularly automatically updated and
therefore less likely to have security
issues it is also often bundles so
as to make it more cost effective.
Individuals can keep their data and
photographs using cloud storage which
may be provided by their internet
provider and have them accessible on
any device, any place and at any time.
Cloud gaming also opens up the world
of gaming making it easier to access
a wider range of new and old games
without having to purchase a hard copy
or download a copy, but with this the
speed of the internet can have an impact.
Abraham: Something we don't
always think of as cyber crime
is 'fake news' and video.
We are noticing more regularly the
term 'fake news' and we have all seen
adds and so-called videos of famous
people endorsing products and services
which have nothing to do with them.
Some people think that everything they see
especially on the internet must be real,
but we are getting more used to seeing how
creative and clever individuals and groups
are at tricking us into believing things.
Fake news is false or misleading
information and can mask itself as
real and when enough people believe
it and it enters the public domain
it can often be seen as 'real'.
There have been many examples of this
recently with regards to vaccines and 5G.
Fake news can even affect
elections and create unrest
nationally and internationally.
Nicole: Deepfakes can be more worrying,
as we say 'seeing is believing' however
technology has advanced so much that
often what we see, should not be believed.
Deep learning technology uses neural
net simulation to create 'fake' video
which can even bring dead people back
to life and acting in today’s movies.
Artificial intelligence learns what a
source face looks like from different
angles and then can transpose it
onto a target usually another actor.
Hollywood has done this in movies such
as 'Rogue One' however, new software
tools have made this available to all.
It can be used for fun and for
training videos, but it can also
be used for gain and for criminal
enterprise convincing people that
celebrities are endorsing a product.
I can also be used to discredit people
using impersonators to create voiceovers.
The potential for creatives and the
film industry is immense but so is
the potential for criminal enterprise.
Abraham: So, there are many things that
have the potential to be affected by
cyber crime but one new advancement is
the use of the technology of drones.
Drone jacking is the way cyber
criminals use toy-like drones to
take control of personal information.
Drones have become an important tool for
farmers, photographers and videographers
and law enforcement and delivery services.
Drone jackers can hack drones
and take control, but they can
also use drones to attack others.
They can cause chaos at airports,
and they can use this technology
for criminal enterprise such
as delivering drugs to prisons,
espionage and worst of all terrorism.
So, we can see that cyber security
is an ever-changing field and can
affect us all directly and indirectly.
It is something that we all must be aware
of and cyber security professionals need
to try to keep ahead of the criminals and
anticipate where they might strike next.